Keep the room well-lit and watch from a distance, okay?
On his way back from buying JUMP, Gin-san gets into an accident on his moped!!]
[(Administrative message) There have been many careless accidents lately. So let's all be on the alert.]
Man, I vowed I would move on from JUMP already...
(銀時)ああ まったく…｡
いいかげんに➡
｢ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ｣は卒業だって
この前 心に誓ったってぇのに➡
So why am I doing this?
どうして
こうなるんだろうなぁ ｵｲ！
やっぱ 週刊連載は
引きが すべてだし➡
Weekly serials are all about the attraction. Once they suck you in, you have to know what happens next week.
引っぱられちゃうと
見たくなっちゃうからな｡
１回 見逃すと
わけわかんなくなるし…｡
You lose track if you miss a single issue, and...
いや だからこそ もう やめに
しとくべきだったのか…｡
No, that's exactly why I should stop...
ﾎﾝﾄ 罪だよなぁ 少年ｼﾞｬ… ん？
This is really a sin... Shonen Jum... Huh?
ﾌﾟ～～～!!
(激突音)
《あれ？ 何だ これ…➡
Huh? What's this? The sky is all red.
空が真っ赤だ》
Huh? It's me that's all red.
《あれ？
真っ赤なのは ｵﾚじゃねえか？
あれ？ なんで ｵﾚ
こんなことになったんだっけ？
Huh? How the hell did this happen?
Huh? Wait a minute, I...
あれ？ ちょっと待て ｵﾚ…》
(新八)ﾊｧ ﾊｧ ﾊｧ…！
みんな～！
(神楽)新八！
Guys!
Shinpachi...
銀さんは？
銀さんは 大丈夫なの!?
Gin-san? Is Gin-san all right?
(お登勢)病院で でけえ声
出すんじゃないよ ﾊﾞｶ野郎～！
Don't shout in a hospital, idiot!
(神楽)ｵﾒｴもな！ ばばあ!!
Same for you, granny!
You, too, brat. And me, too!
(ｷｬｻﾘﾝ)ｵﾒｴもな！ ｸｿｶﾞｷ!!
そして 私もさぁ～！
(お登勢)ﾌﾝ！ 心配いらんよ｡
Hmph... Nothing to worry about.
車に はねられたくらいで
死ぬﾀﾏかい｡
He's not the type to die from getting hit by a car.
｢ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ｣買いに行ったときに
はねられたらしいね｡
They say he got hit when he went out to buy JUMP.
いい歳こいて
こんなん読んでるから➡
That's what happens when you read this kind of junk at his age.
こんな目に遭うｱﾙ｡
(ｷｬｻﾘﾝ)これを機会に➡
Let's hope he'll take this opportunity to grow up a bit.
少しは
大人になってほしいものですね｡
(お登勢)まったくだ｡
(加害者)いやぁ～…！
You said it.
You know...
Hearing you say that makes me feel better.
(加害者)そう言ってもらえると
はねたこっちも 気が楽っす｡
ﾏｼﾞ すんませんでした｡
I'm really sorry.
I was talking on my cell phone and didn't see him in time.
ｹｰﾀｲでしゃべってたら
確認 遅れちゃって…！
ﾃﾒｴか この野郎～！
おらぁ～ 飛べこらぁ～！
So you're the bastard!
Let's see how far you can fly!! I'm sending you to the moon!
If Gin-chan dies, I'll strangle you to death with your own cell phone strap!
銀ちゃんが死んだら ﾃﾒｴ
絞首刑にして➡
ｹｰﾀｲｽﾄﾗｯﾌﾟにしてやっからなぁ!!
やっぱ ﾀﾞﾒかもしれない…｡
Maybe he's not okay, after all...
Keep it quiet! Where do you idiots think you are?!
(婦長)うっせえ～!!
ここ どこだと思ってんだ？
ﾊﾞｶどもがぁ～!!
(医師)いや ｷﾐもうるさい｡
Look who's talking.
(騒ぎ声)
Hey! You can't go in there yet!
Hey, he looks fine.
なんだい…
全然 元気じゃないかい｡
You scared the hell out of us! I won't let you buy JUMP anymore!
(神楽)心配かけて！
もう ｢ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ｣なんて➡
買わせないからね！
心配しましたよ 銀さん｡
We were worried, Gin-san... You sure hit some bad luck, huh?
えらい目に遭いましたね｡
Who are you?
誰？
えっ!?
Do I know you people?
いったい 誰だい？ ｷﾐたちは｡
ﾎﾞｸの知り合いなのかい？
Do we know each other?
["You Always Remember the Things that Matter the Least"]
(新八たち)ええ～!! 記憶喪失!?
Amnesia?!
(医師)
ｹｶﾞは どうってことないんだがね｡
His injuries aren't that bad.
頭を強く打ったらしくて➡
He hit his head real hard, and that must have made some of his memories pop out.
その拍子に 記憶も ﾎﾟﾛｰﾝと
落としてきちゃったみたいだね｡
"Pop out"?! What is he, a toaster?!
落としたって… そんな自転車の鍵
みたいな言い方 やめてください｡
(医師)事故前後の記憶が
ちょこっと消えるってのは➡
It's common for someone to lose their memory of what happened before and after an accident.
よくあるんだがねぇ｡
In his case, he seems to have also forgotten his entire identity.
彼の場合 自分の存在も
忘れてるみたいで➡
ちょっと やっかいだなぁ｡
That could be quite a problem.
You'd better not be faking this.
ﾃﾒｴ ｳｿついてんじゃねえぞ！
This fool doesn't have amnesia.  He just wants to get out of paying rent.
記憶喪失のﾌﾘして
家賃ごまかすつもりだろ？
Doctor... I think I'm hallucinating, too. I keep seeing this hideous goblin.
先生 さっきから 病室に
老婆の妖怪が見えるんですが➡
これも
頭を打った 影響なんですか？
坂田さん 心配いらないよ｡
Sakata-san, there's nothing to worry about.
There are no goblins in this hospital. Maybe a ghost or two...
それは 妖怪じゃない｡
ここは 病院だぞ｡
幽霊くらい出る｡
Doctor, that's not right.
先生 違います｡
(医師)
人間の記憶は 木の枝のように➡
The human memory is very complex, like a tree with its branches intertwined.
複雑に絡み合ってできている｡
その枝の１本でも
ざわめかせれば➡
If one branch is disturbed, the others move, too.
他の枝も 徐々に
動き始めていきますよ｡
まぁ 焦らず 気長に
診ていきましょう｡
Let's just see how it goes for a while.
万事屋銀ちゃん｡
Odd Jobs Gin... Is this where I live?
ここが ﾎﾞｸの住まいなんですか？
そうです｡ 銀さんは ここで➡
That's right, Gin-san. You take on odd jobs... A freelancer.
なんでも屋を
営んでいたんですよ｡
Odd Jobs... It's no use, I don't remember.
なんでも屋… ﾀﾞﾒだ
何も思い出せない｡
まぁ なんでも屋っつうか
ほとんど➡
An Odd Jobs who did practically nothing at all. We were like paupers.
何もやってない屋ｱﾙ｡
ﾌﾟｰ太郎だったある｡
ﾌﾟｰ？ この歳で ﾌﾟｰ？
Pau...?!
Paupers at my age?!
おまけに 年中
死んだ魚のような目をして➡
To make matters worse, you always look like a walking corpse with dead fish eyes.
ぐ～たら生きる
屍のような男だったｱﾙ｡
And you didn't pay the rent.
家賃も払わないしねぇ｡
And you also stole Otose-san's money.
あと お登勢さんのお金
強奪とかしてましたよね｡
それは お前だろうが！
That was you!
中に入ってみたら 何か
思い出すかもしれませんよ｡
You might remember something if you go inside.
This is your home, Gin-san. Doesn't it bring back memories?
ここが 銀さんの家ですよ｡
なんとなく
懐かしいんじゃないですか？
That's right! You always sat on this sofa, digging your boogers!
(神楽)そうｱﾙ！
いつも このｿﾌｧに座って➡
鼻ｸｿほじって ぼやいてたｱﾙ｡
ほら 銀ちゃん！ 定春ｱﾙよ ほら!!
Look, Gin-chan!
It's Sadaharu. See?
うわぁ～… って でか！
Humongous! What'd you feed him to make him this big?
何食べさせたら こんなになるの？
銀ちゃん いつも定春のこと
かわいがってたｱﾙよ｡
Gin-chan, you were always fond of Sadaharu.
こんな 非常識なｻｲｽﾞの犬を➡
How could I be fond of a ridiculously sized dog like this?
ﾎﾞｸが かわいがるなんてこと…｡
(定春)ｶﾌﾟｯ｡
あっ！
It's pitch black. I can't see a thing.
真っ暗で 何も見えなくなったぞ｡
Could my mind be unconsciously trying to seal away my memories?
これは もしかして ﾎﾞｸの心が➡
無意識に記憶を
封印しようとしているのか？
いや… そうじゃないから｡
No, that's not it. You've been bitten, that's quite normal really.
噛みつかれてますから 普通に…｡
っていうか 意識が なんか➡
My...
consciousness is fading away...
ｽ～ｯと 遠くなっているような…｡
って神楽ちゃん！
血 出てるから!!
Kagura-chan! He's bleeding!
He'll lose his consciousness as well as his memory!
記憶どころか
意識もってかれちゃうからさ！
Do something quickly!
早く なんとかしてぇ!!
ﾌｩ～…｡
♪♪～
Look, it's your favorite: Ms. Ketsuno.
ほら！ 銀さんの好きな
結野ｱﾅですよ｡
(神楽)いつも 朝の占い
ﾛｳｱﾝｸﾞﾙから➡
You'd always peer at her from a low angle during her morning forecast!
食い入るように
覗き込んでたｱﾙよ｡
ｹﾂのｱﾅ？
Ketsuno, Ana?
Well? Do you remember anything?
どうです？
何か思い出しました？
あ～ 思い出せないっつうか
思い出したくないんですけど…｡
I don't remember...or rather, I don't want to remember...
Pull yourself together!
しっかりしろ～!!
もっと ﾀﾞﾒになれ！
Be a loser! Discard your conscience. That's who GINTOKI is!
良心なんか捨てちまえ！
それが 銀時だぁ！
えっ そうなんですか？
(神楽)それが 銀時なんだ！
Is that so?
That's who GINTOKI is!  He's a sore, sore, sore, loser!!
お登勢さん どうしましょう？
Otose-san, what should we do?
ﾌｩ～…｡
江戸の町 ぶらりと回ってきな｡
Walk him down the streets of Edo.
ｺｲﾂは 江戸中に 枝張ってる男だ｡
This is a man with connections throughout Edo.
記憶呼び覚ますきっかけなんて
そこら中 転がってるだろう｡
You might stumble across something that might strike a chord in his memory.
(馬の鳴き声)
What? Amnesia?
(桂)なに？ 記憶喪失？
Is this true? Tell me the details of what happened, Gintoki.
それは 本当か？
何があったか詳しく教えろ 銀時｡
だから 記憶がないって
言ってるでしょうが…｡
As I said, he lost his memories.
ってか 桂さん
何やってるんですか？
By the way, what're you doing here, Katsura-san?
国を救うにも 何をするにも
まず 金がいるということさ｡
To save the country, first you've got to have money.
そこのおにいさん
ちょっと寄ってって！
Hey, bro! Come on in! We got hot chicks here.
かわいい娘 いっぱいいるよ｡
I know, Gintoki, why don't you stop by, too. We have lots of pretties.
そうだ 銀時
お前も寄っていけ｡
[All you can drink! All you can grope!]
きれいなねえちゃん
いっぱいだぞ｡
You'll be able to forget all the bad memories.
ｲﾔなことなんか 忘れられるぞ｡
Hasn't he forgotten enough already?!
これ以上 何を
忘れさせるつもりですか！
ｱﾝﾀら ﾎﾝﾄ 友達!?
Are you really friends?!
何か 思い出せそうな気がする｡
I feel a memory stirring!
行ってみよう｡
ｳｿつけえ～～!!
Let's check it out.
Liar!!
あぁっ！ 今ので 何かきそう！
I felt something just now! It's coming...!
何か ここまできてる！
本当か！
Really? Remember, Gintoki!
思い出せ 銀時！
お前は ｵﾚの舎弟として➡
Remember the days when you slaved as my apprentice!
日々 こき使われていたんだ！
おい～～!!
Hey! Don't go changing his memory!
記憶 勝手に改ざんするなぁ!!
ｸﾞﾊｯ！
(殴る音)
どの辺ｱﾙか？
Where is it? Where do I hit to jog your memory? Here? Here?
どの辺 叩かれたら
記憶が刺激された？
ここｱﾙか？ ここか？
いや この辺だろ｡
No, it's probably around here.
あれ？ この辺か？
ここか？ ここか!?
No? Then here?
Oh no, no... Stop it!
あ～あ～！ やめてやめて！
やめてよ もう！
(土方)ん？ 何の騒ぎだ？
ｹﾝｶか？
[Shinsengumi]
What's going on? Is it a fight? It's been a while. Think we should jump in?
久しぶりにやるか… おっ？
(土方)ありゃ？ 桂～～!!
Hey, that's...
Katsura!
(衝撃音)
やったか？
(沖田)あれ？
Did you get him?
(沖田)こんな荷物
ありましたっけ？
Is this ours?
総悟… 逃げるぞ｡
(沖田)え？
Sogo, run.
(爆発音)
Hmph. Stupid samurai should stay home and play with their swords.
ﾌﾝ 芋侍が…｡
家で ﾁｬﾝﾊﾞﾗごっこでも
しているがいい…！
No!
(土方)いや！ 今日は
つきあってもらうぜ 桂！
You're playing with us today, Katsura!
ﾌﾝ… やるな 逃げるぞ ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ！
Hmph, not bad. Run, Elizabeth.
(土方)待ちやがれぇ～っ！
Come back here!
(２人)あっ！
(神楽)銀ちゃん！
Gin-chan!
Gin-san!
銀さん！ 銀さん
しっかりしてよ 銀さん!!
Gin-san! Are you okay, Gin-san?!
ｷﾐたちは… 誰だ？
Who are you people?
What? Amnesia?!
(さっちゃん)えぇっ！ 記憶喪失!?
What is that? A new kind of play?
それって何？ 新しいﾌﾟﾚｲ？
いや… もう いいんですけどね｡
No, never mind. If they can hear each other, they can converse...
聞こえるなら
会話は 成立しますから…｡
This is Candid Camera, isn't it?
ﾄﾞｯｷﾘなんでしょ？
I can tell you're all trying to deceive me to get your kicks.
みんなで 私を陥れて
喜ばそうって魂胆が 見え見えよ｡
ちなみに… ｶﾒﾗは どこなの？
By the way, where's the camera?
違いますよ
正真正銘の 記憶喪失です｡
You've got it all wrong. He actually has amnesia.
ｳｿ… それって つまり…｡
You're lying. That means...
Yes...
He's completely forgotten all the embarrassing things he did
私とした
あんな恥ずかしいことや➡
with me and all those painful experiences that came with it?
こんな痛みの伴う体験も
全部 忘れちゃったってこと!?
あの あなたとﾎﾞｸは いったい➡
Um, what is your relationship to me?
どういう関係なんですか？
How cruel! We were on the brink of being married!
ひどいわ！
結婚寸前までいった間柄なのに➡
紋付袴まで 着てくれたのに!!
You even wore formal wedding wear!
いや… まぁ
そうなんでしょうけど…｡
Well, yes, but...
都合のいい事実だけ口にする｡
You only say the facts that are convenient to you.
たちの悪い 詐欺師の手口ｱﾙ｡
Those are the tricks of an evil con artist.
それじゃ あなたはﾎﾞｸの…｡
Then are you my...
そうよ 銀さん…｡
That's right, Gin-san!
I am your love S-L-A-V-E!
私は あなたの 愛の ﾄﾞ･ﾚ･ｲ･だ･ぞ｡
なにそれ なんなのよ 放置ﾌﾟﾚｲ？
Why're you doing this to me?
Is this a kind of abandonment role-play fantasy?
それは それでｼﾋﾞれるけど➡
That turns me on, too, but that's not the normal you, Gin-san!
そんなの いつもの
銀さんじゃないわっ！
We've been trying to tell you Gin-chan isn't his normal self.
だから いつもの銀ちゃんじゃ
ないって言ってるｱﾙ｡
あの… なんなんですか？ この人｡
Who is this person?
このままじゃ ｱﾌﾞﾉｰﾏﾙが移ります｡
At this rate, you'll catch her abnormality. Let's go, Gin-san.
行きましょう 銀さん｡
そうは させない…｡
I won't let you...
銀さんは 他の誰にも
渡さないわ～っ！
I won't let anyone else have Gin-san!
(爆発音)
(神楽)うぇっ！
なにｱﾙか これ くさっ!!
Phew! What is this stench?!
ｹﾞﾎｯ ｹﾞﾎｯ… 煙玉の中に
無意味に納豆が!?
There was natto in that smoke bomb!
あっ 銀ちゃんが いない！
えぇっ？
Gin-chan's gone!
♪♪～
Uh, why're you doing this?
あの… これは
どういうことなのでしょうか？
大丈夫よ 銀さん… 私に任せて｡
It's all right, Gin-san. Leave everything to me. I won't hurt you.
絶対に 悪いようには しないわ｡
いや… 悪いようには
しないって言う人ほど➡
No, grandma always said, you can't trust the people who say they won't hurt you.
信用できないと おばあちゃんが
言ってたんですが…｡
いた！ あそこだっ!!
Ouch.
There!
逃がさないｱﾙ！
You're not getting away!
(銃声)
♪♪～
甘いわね…
この程度の攻撃で この私を…｡
Too easy. You can't get me with that kind of attack.
安心して… 私の すべてを
教えて あ･げ･る｡
Don't worry. I'll teach you everything about me.
いや… ﾎﾞｸが知りたいのは
ﾎﾞｸの記憶なんですけど…｡
I just want to know about my own memory.
Gin-san, knowing about me means knowing about yourself.
銀さん 私を知るってことは➡
あなた自身を
知ることでもあるのよ｡
ほちゃあぁ～っ はっ！
１DKの 日当たりのいい部屋を
借りましょう｡
Let's rent a small studio apartment.
そこから 私たちの
新しい第一歩が 始まるのよ！
That'll be the first step of our new beginning.
As for kids, one boy and one girl would be nice, too.
子供は 男女 一人ずつが
いいわよね｡
ｽﾃｷな名前を 考えなくちゃ！
そうね 猿飛…｡
We'll think of wonderful names for them. Sarutobi...
だから 勝手に
決めてんじゃねえよ！
Stop deciding things on your own!
お前なんかと 第一歩なんて
踏み出したくねえんだよ！
I don't want to take my first steps with you!
あ… なんか いつもの
胸を締め付ける そのｾﾘﾌ…｡
Those words squeeze my heart as strong as they did before!
銀ちゃんは 渡さないｱﾙ!!
(銃声)
I won't let you have Gin-chan!
ほちゃあぁ～っ！
(銃声)
♪♪～
You think...
そんなんで 私を➡
You can stop me with that?
止められるとでも 思っていたの？
Huh...
あれ… 銀さんは？
Where'd Gin-san go...?
(神楽)あっ 銀ちゃん！
Gin-chan!
銀さ～ん！
Gin-san!
大丈夫 間に合う！
受け止めてみせる!!
I can make it in time! I'll break his fall!
♪♪～
って なんでﾌﾙｽｲﾝｸﾞ!?
意味わかんないからさ！
Why'd you take a full swing?!
I don't understand!
湿っぽい空気は
『銀魂』に 似合わないｱﾙよ！
Doing it half-heartedly isn't like Gin Tama.
That's no reason to "wham" him!
だからって 打つな！
Gin-san! Gin-san!
銀さん 銀さんってば！
Gin-chan, are you alive?
銀ちゃ～ん 生きてるｱﾙか？
Hey, are you okay?
ちょっと… 大丈夫ですか!?
ここは… どこだ？
What is this place?
♪♪～
My, that's awful.
(お妙)まぁ そう…
それは大変だったわね｡
じゃあ 私のことも
忘れてしまったのかしら？
Has he forgotten about me, too?
すみません…｡
I'm sorry.
私のことは 覚えているわよね？
You still remember me, right?
No, he said, "I'm sorry."
いや… すみませんって
言ったじゃないですか｡
いや 覚えてるわよ
ふざけんじゃないわよ｡
No, he remembers. Don't play dumb with me.
You mean I remember him, but he doesn't remember me? That sucks!
(お妙)私が覚えているのに
一方的に 忘れられるなんて➡
胸ｸｿ悪いわ 何様？
Who does he think he is?
新ちゃん… これで私を殴って➡
Shin-chan, hit me with this so I forget my memories of Gin-san.
銀さんの記憶だけ
取り除いてちょうだい｡
姉上… ﾎﾞｸ ｴｽﾊﾟｰ？
Sis, what am I, a brain surgeon?!
ﾌｯ… じゃあ しかたないわ｡
Then I have no choice.
是が非でも
思い出してもらうわよ～！
I'll make you remember me, no matter what!
(神楽/新八)うわっ！
同じｼｮｯｸを与えれば➡
If I duplicate the shock, I'm sure he'll remember!
きっと よみがえるわ！
ｱﾈｺﾞ ｶﾝﾍﾞﾝしてくだせえ！
Sis, not that! You'll put us back where we started!
また 振り出しに戻っちゃうよ！
すみません… 今は
まだ 思い出せませんが➡
I'm sorry. I still cannot remember you, but I know I will soon.
必ず あなたのことも
思い出しますので➡
それまで しばし ご辛抱を…｡
Please just be patient.
えっ…｡
What...?
ｲﾔだわ… なに？
Oh my, why is my heart pounding over someone like Gin-san?
銀さんごときで
ﾄﾞｷﾄﾞｷするなんて…｡
あんなの ただ 目と眉が➡
His eyes and eyebrows just look closer together...that's all.
ちょっと近づいただけじゃないの｡
And his pupils are bigger...that's all.
黒目が ちょっと
でかくなっただけじゃないの｡
ｱﾈｺﾞ？
Sis?
もう 過去のことは いいじゃない｡
Forget the past.
Live looking forward rather than backwards.
後ろを振り返るより
前を見て 生きていきましょう｡
What?! You changed your mind! Why?!
なにぃ!? 急に変わったよ！
何があったんですかっ!!
(お妙)昔の銀さんは封印して➡
Lock up that worthless old Gin-san and live your life as the new Gin-san.
これからは ﾆｭｰ銀さんとして
生きていきなさい｡
Big Sis! That's like putting a cover on smelly things to hide them!
姉上！ それじゃ
臭い物にﾌﾀの原理ですよ！
Did I say smelly?
あっ 臭い物って言っちゃった…｡
What do I see in a man with dead-fish eyes, anyways?
あんな 目と眉の離れた男の
どこがいいのよ｡
ﾁｬﾗﾝﾎﾟﾗﾝな銀さんより
今のほうが 真面目そうだし…｡
I prefer Gin-san the way he is now, compared to that frivolous Gin-san.
ｽ… ｽﾃｷじゃない…｡
He's almost... Handsome...
なに 頬 染めてるんですか！
Why are your cheeks so red? You're blushing!
You're not in love with him, are you?!
まさか 惚れたんですか!?
認めん 認めんぞ!!
No way! I won't allow it!
あんな男の義弟になるなんて
ﾎﾞｸは 絶対ｲﾔです！
I absolutely refuse to become this creep's brother-in-law!
話を飛躍させるんじゃありません｡
This isn't about you.
(近藤)そうですよ！
今は 目と眉が近づいてますが➡
She's right! His eyes and eyebrows may be closer together now,
記憶が戻れば また離れますよ！
but when his memory returns, they'll separate again!
また 締まりのない
顔になりますよ！
He'll be back to that loose face!
♪♪～
What're you doing here?
(お妙)何をしてんだ ﾃﾒｴは！
Well, it was just so toasty and warm... I fell asleep...
(近藤)いや…
あったかそうだったんで➡
つい 寝ちゃって…｡
Here...
(近藤)あの… これ…｡
I bought some Bäagen-Dazs for everyone.
お土産に ﾊﾞｰｹﾞﾝﾀﾞｯｼｭ
買ってきたんで➡
みんなで 食べてくだしゃい｡
It's melted and gooey! How long have you been under there?!
溶けてﾄﾞﾛﾄﾞﾛじゃないですか！
ｱﾝﾀ いったい 何時間
こたつの中にいたの!?
よぉ… 久しぶりだな｡
So, we meet again.
I haven't seen you in a while. You've changed quite a bit.
しばらく会わんうちに➡
ずいぶんとｲﾒｰｼﾞが
変わったんじゃないか？
Are you trying to use amnesia to change your image and seduce Otae-san?
記憶喪失を利用して
ｲﾒﾁｪﾝをはかり➡
お妙さんを口説こうって魂胆か｡
(近藤)だが そうはいかんぞ｡
I won't let you.
お前なんかより ｵﾚのほうが➡
My eyes and eyebrows are way closer together than yours!
目と眉が近いもんね～！
ﾊﾊﾊﾊﾊ～！
見てください お妙さん これ！
Look at me, Otae-san.
江戸じゅう探しても こんな
目と眉が近いﾔﾂは いないよ！
You can search all of Edo, but you will never find eyes and brows closer together than these!
I couldn't love a stalker even if he had hair growing out of his eyes!
ｽﾄｰｶｰをするような人は➡
目から毛が生えてても
好きにはなれません｡
(近藤)わかった！ じゃあ
目より下に 毛 生やすから…！
All right. So what if I grow hair below my eyes? How about that?
Wh-What is this? How odd...I feel like as this cup is drawing me towards it.
こ これは…｡
How about it? You'd be a monster!
なんだろう？ 不思議だ｡
体が 勝手に 引き寄せられる｡
あっ 甘いもの！
Oh! Sugar!
(神楽)そうね！
甘いもの食べさせたら➡
That's right! Sugar might jog his memory!
記憶が
よみがえるかもしれないよ！
うりゃあっ！ 食え この野郎!!
Eat it!
姉上 甘いものです！
Sis! Gather every dessert in the house!
家じゅうの甘いものを
かき集めてください！
え… なに？
いいから 甘いもの！
Huh? What?
Just get something sweet!
そんなこと言われたって！
But I don't...
銀ちゃん 戻ってきてよ！
銀ちゃん！
Gin-chan come back to us! Gin-chan!
う…｡
I...I...I...
ﾎﾞ ﾎﾞｸは… ﾎﾞｸは…｡
ｵﾚは…｡
I'm...
銀ちゃん！
銀さ…｡
Gin-chan!
Gin-sa...
たぁっ！
ぐぼっ!!
姉上 なんですか？ それは…｡
Big Sis, what is that?
卵焼きよ｡
A tamagoyaki omelet. I made it extra sweet today.
今日は 甘めに作ってみたから｡
This omelet has quite a unique taste...
いやぁ
なかなか 個性的な味ですなぁ➡
この卵焼… うぅ｡
近藤さん！ 銀さん！
Kondo-san!
Gin-san!
(２人)ｷﾐたちは 誰だ？
Who...are...you...people?
(お妙)まぁ かわいい｡
My, how cute...
♪♪～
すみません… いろいろ
手を尽くしてくれたのに➡
I'm sorry. You've tried everything, for me, but in the end, I can't remember anything.
結局 ﾎﾞｸは 何にも…｡
Stop it! It's not like you!
やめてくださいよ｡ らしくもない｡
Even if you're 90% wrong, you'll use everything you have of that last 10% to not apologize!
銀さんは
90ﾊﾟｰｾﾝﾄ 自分が悪くても➡
残りの10ﾊﾟｰｾﾝﾄに
全身全霊をかけて➡
謝らない人ですよ｡
ゆっくり思い出せばいいね｡
Take your time to remember. We'll wait.
私たち 待ってるｱﾙから｡
Let's go home and take it easy.
今日は 家に帰って
ゆっくり休みましょ｡
(神楽)そうね
家で まったりしてれば➡
Yes, you might remember something if you just relax at home.
何か思い出すかも｡
(男)なんだ あれは！
What's that?!
あれは… 宇宙船!?
That's...
A spaceship?!
大変だ！ まっすぐ
こっちへ落っこちてきますよ！
Oh no! It's coming straight at us!
Gin-chan! Gin-chan, it's time for you to do your thing!
銀ちゃん！ 銀ちゃんの出番ｱﾙよ！
え？
What?
銀さん 早く！
あの…｡
Gin-san, quickly!
Uh, um...
(神楽)ほわちゃ～！
あぁっ！
さぁ 銀ちゃん！
あの すみません…｡
Now, Gin-chan.
Um, excuse me, just what am I supposed to do?
いったい
どうすればいいんですか？
Chi! Use your chi! You always do something with your chi!
気合いｱﾙよ 気合い｡
銀ちゃんは いつも
気合いで 何とかしてたｱﾙよ！
That's right.
そうですよ 巨大ﾛﾎﾞだろうが
大量破壊兵器だろうが➡
Whether it's a giant robot or a weapon of mass destruction,
銀さんは これ１本で
切り抜けてきたんですよ！
you've always slashed your way through with just this sword!
これで…？
With this...?
You can definitely do it, Gin-chan!
銀ちゃんだったら 絶対できるｱﾙ！
お願いします 銀さん！
Please do it! Gin-san!
ﾎﾞｸは…｡
I...
Gin-chan!
(神楽)銀ちゃん！
銀さん！
Gin-san!
ﾎﾞｸが…！
Me?!
♪♪～
(神楽)銀ちゃん…｡
Gin-chan...
ﾑﾘですよ｡
There's no way...
人間が そんな便利になれるわけ
ないじゃないですか｡
No human being can accomplish such a thing.
あれ？ あっちって
万事屋のほうじゃないの!?
Huh? Isn't that in the direction of Odd Jobs?
(銀時/神楽)えっ？
(野次馬)おいおい
派手に やりやがったなぁ｡
That was intense.
(野次馬)ありゃ もう
建て直さないとﾀﾞﾒじゃないの？
It's totaled. They'll have to rebuild.
い… 家が！
Our house...
(坂本)ｱﾊﾊﾊﾊ すみませ～ん｡
Sorry about that!
友達の家ば行こうとしちょったら
道に迷うてしまってのぅ｡
I was trying to get to a friend's place, but I got lost.
I ran out of fuel as I was circling about, and crashed here.
(坂本)ｸﾞﾙｸﾞﾙと回っとったら
ｶﾞｽ欠で 落っこちてしもうたきに｡
ｱﾊﾊﾊﾊ～｡
この辺に 万事屋 金ちゃんって
店は ありませんかのぅ？
Is there an Odd Jobs Kin-chan around here?
(同心)万事屋 銀ちゃんなら
ｱﾝﾀの突っ込んだ家ですけどね｡
If it's Odd Jobs Gin you're looking for, it's the place you destroyed.
No, no, it's Kin-chan.
違う違う 金ちゃんじゃ｡
(坂本)お前 なにを聞いとるんじゃ
そそっかしかﾔﾂじゃのぅ｡
Weren't you listening? You're not paying attention.
(坂本)ｱﾊﾊﾊﾊ～ ｱﾊ｡
(弥七)わかった わかった｡
Yeah, yeah, we heard you. Come with us to the station.
(弥七)じゃあ とりあえず
署まで来てもらうから｡
Oh, you'll show me to Kintoki's place?
(坂本)おっ 金時のｳﾁまで
案内してくれるがか！
(坂本)江戸っ子は親切じゃのぅ｡
すまんのぅ ｱﾊﾊﾊ～｡
People in Edo are so nice. Thanks.
You're obnoxious. Keep quiet.
(同心)ｵﾒｴ うっせえから
少し黙ってろよ！
(ｻｲﾚﾝ)
Now what are we gonna do?  We've even lost the house.
どうしましょう…
家まで なくなっちゃった｡
♪♪～
《ﾎﾞｸは
いったい 何者なんだろう…》
Who am I...?
Gin-chan!
銀ちゃん
大丈夫ｱﾙよ 何とかなるｱﾙ｡
We'll be all right. We'll manage somehow.
That's right. When your memory returns, I'm sure we'll joke about this.
そうそう 記憶が戻れば
きっと 笑い話になってますから｡
とりあえず
今日の寝床を探しましょう｡
For the time being, we have to find somewhere else to stay.
Why are these two people...
《この２人は どうして…》
You've done enough. Don't worry about me.
もういいですよ
ﾎﾞｸのことは 放っておいて｡
みんな
帰るところがあるんでしょう？
You both have homes to go back to, don't you?
ﾎﾞｸのことは気にせずに
自由になってください｡
Don't worry about me. Be free.
銀さん？
Gin-san?
From what I've heard, I made you both work without any real salary.
聞けば 給料も ろくにもらわず
働かされていたようですし➡
こうなった今
残る理由もないでしょう｡
After this, there's no reason for you to stick around.
記憶も住まいも失って➡
Now that I've lost my memory and my house... All the evidence I ever existed is gone.
ﾎﾞｸが この世に生きてきた証しは
なくなってしまった｡
But this might be a good opportunity.
でも これも
いい機会かもしれない｡
みんなの話じゃ ﾎﾞｸも
ﾑﾁｬｸﾁｬな男だったらしいし➡
According to everyone's stories, I was a real mess of a guy.
This is my chance to start all over again.
生まれ変わったつもりで
生き直してみようかな って｡
So let's end this "Odd Jobs" business.
だから… 万事屋は
ここで 解散しましょう｡
ｳ… ｳｿでしょ？ 銀さん！
You're kidding, right, Gin-san?
(神楽)やぁよ！
私 給料なんて いらない！
I don't need a salary!
酢ｺﾝﾌﾞで ｶﾞﾏﾝするから！
ねぇ 銀ちゃん！
All I need is a little pickled seaweed! So please, Gin-chan!
I'm sorry. The Gin-san you both knew isn't here anymore.
すまない…
ｷﾐたちの知っている銀さんは➡
もう ﾎﾞｸの中には いないよ｡
It won't work! You can't function in society! You're an idiot!
ﾑﾘよ！ ｵﾒｴ 社会適応力ｾﾞﾛだから！
ﾊﾞｶだから!!
銀さん！
ちょっと待ってくださいよ!!
Gin-san! Please wait!
Gin-chan!
(神楽)銀ちゃん！
銀さ～ん!!
Gin-saaan!
[Preview]
Thank you, everyone watching us on TV, for your support.
It looks like Odd Jobs really is going to close down.
Gin-san went off somewhere, but we'll wait forever.
The next episode: "Life Moves on Like a Conveyor Belt."
[Gintoki, Shinpachi and Kagura go their separate ways.]
[Farewell, Odd Jobs. Farewell, Gin Tama.]
I've decided to relive my life.
ﾎﾞｸは 生き直そうと
心に決めたんだ｡